Hello. I'm in Sokotai.
哈囉 我現在在素可泰
I took the car yesterday at 9:00 p.m.
我昨天搭晚上9點的車
The bus stop over here at 4:00 a.m.
早上4點的時候到這邊的巴士站
I met a great aunt in the car.
我在車上遇到一個很好的阿姨
She called me a cab. It's a motorcycle.
她幫我叫計程車 就是摩托車
Take me to where I live now.
載我到現在我住的這裡
I was actually asleep.
我剛剛其實已經睡了一覺
Maybe find something to eat.
可能去找點東西吃
Then we'll go to Ancient City for a little bit.
然後再去古城那邊逛一逛
I just washed my hair.
我剛才洗了頭
Wash your face, bathe your face.
洗了臉 洗了澡
All right, let's go.
好 那就出發
I'm in.
我進來了
The bike I borrowed from the door.
我剛在門口借的腳踏車
Here it is.
在這裡
This is the bike I borrowed.
這是我借的腳踏車
30 bucks.
30塊
It's just a normal car. There's no speed change.
就普通的車 沒有變速的
Because I can't read the map either.
因為我也看不懂地圖
I can't tell from that position.
那個位置我分不出來
Everyone looks so much alike.
每個都長得太像了
It's the first thing I've ever seen.
是我現在看到的第一個
It feels perfect.
感覺很完整
His leaves are so low.
它的葉子垂得好低
I don't know what it is.
不知道是什麼
I'll rest here.
我在這邊休息
There's a funny thing.
有一個很有趣的事情
That's the bike.
就是這個腳踏車
I just saw this sticker.
我剛看到有貼這種貼紙
That's why the Japanese don't want this car.
所以這台車是日本人不要
I'll give it back to you.
然後拿來報廢的吧
It's still written on it.
它上面還有寫
Osaka P.D.
大阪府警察
I think so.
應該是吧
Looks like an old car, too.
看起來也是很舊的車
But it's still a good ride.
不過還是很好騎
There's a big sun out there.
現在外面太陽很大
Maybe it's dryer.
可能比較乾吧
I'm just feeling...
就覺得
It's hot, but it's not coming.
雖然很熱可是不會到
I've been sweating a lot.
一直流汗很不舒服
Maybe I'll stay until night.
我可能會待到晚上吧
I'll probably find something to eat later.
我等一下可能去找個東西吃
It's gonna be here till 9:00.
看是這裡會開到9點
Then there'll be lights.
然後會有燈光
Then I'll hang around here.
那我就在這邊隨便亂晃
Just stay until the night.
就待到晚上吧
The sun's smaller now.
現在太陽比較小了
I feel so much better.
我覺得舒服很多
It's a cold weather.
就是涼涼的天氣
Otherwise, it's really hot in the morning.
不然早上那個真的好熱
Then I'll go now.
然後現在去
Outside.
外面
It's a long way from here.
比較遠就騎過去
It's a beautiful day.
現在天氣超棒的
You can go up with this.
這個可以上去吧
A lot of ants.
好多螞蟻
I think so.
應該是可以吧
Whoo!
嗚
There's pigeons up there.
上面有鴿子
I think there's a smell in there.
裡面好像有個香
I think we can do this bye-bye.
應該是可以在這邊拜拜
There's wax here.
這邊有蠟
It's like people don't get here much better.
好像大家比較不會到這裡
I'm wandering around.
我在到處亂晃
It's 4:30 p.m.
現在是下午四點半
Let's go for a walk in the temple.
去廟裡面逛一逛
And then, actually,
然後其實
It's hot though.
雖然現在很熱
Thirty-three, thirty-four degrees of this weather.
33 34度這種天氣
But it's dryer here.
可是這邊比較乾燥
That's why it doesn't feel so uncomfortable.
所以感覺其實不會很不舒服
In fact, it doesn't sweat in the sun.
其實這樣曬在太陽也不會流汗
It's just that you're gonna feel hot.
就是你會覺得很熱
Maybe my clothes are black, too.
可能我衣服也是黑色的
And then it gets hot.
然後就會覺得很熱
But it's not like you're sweaty and sticky.
可是不會到那種流汗黏黏的不舒服
I don't know why they all have one of these.
我不知道為什麼他們都會有一個這種
Then we'll go with one.
然後跟一個
This one seems to be working again.
這個好像才是又在使用的
The temple.
寺廟
I don't know what that is.
這個我不知道是什麼
I wonder if it's possible.
我猜有沒有可能是
The place where the ashes are laid.
放骨灰的地方
I don't know.
我也不知道
Go inside and take a look.
進去看一看
And then there's usually a lot of birds here.
然後通常這邊都有很多鳥
Then there'll be bird shit on the floor.
然後地上都會有鳥大便啊
That's how it feels to climb up there.
這可以爬上去的感覺
I think it's beautiful.
我覺得這個很漂亮
It's like that big palace in Bangkok.
很像那個曼谷的大皇宮
It's beautiful.
很漂亮
Get up there and take a look.
爬上去看一看
Ooh.
哦
And lock it up.
還有關起來
I can't get this up.
這個上不去
What's up there, $10,000?
（應該是大家捐錢蓋的）上面有什麼1萬
Two hundred and fifty thousand.
25萬
And then the little one up there...
然後上面那個小的是
Thousands of dollars.
幾千塊
I'm going now.
我現在去
New City.
新城那邊
I think this is a quiet little city.
我覺得這裡就是一個很安靜的小城市
I think this is where the locals live.
我覺得這裡是很當地人生活的地方
Maybe most tourists are on the side of History Park.
可能大部分遊客都在歷史公園那一邊
I don't know where everyone lives.
不知道大家都會住在哪邊
There's some hotels here too.
在這裡也有一些飯店
But I got a ride back yesterday.
可是我昨天搭車回來
I'm alone.
也只有我一個人
I don't think there's anyone in line for a ride or anything like that.
好像也沒有人排隊要搭之類的
And the coffee shop.
還有咖啡店
I don't know much about coffee, though.
雖然我不太會咖啡
Their laundry.
他們的洗衣店
You have to take off your shoes. It's so special.
連進去都要脫鞋子 好特別
It's six o'clock.
現在已經六點了
And then everybody's out on the street.
然後大家都出來擺攤
The chairs are out.
椅子都擺出來了
Then someone's already eating.
然後已經有人在吃飯了
They're roasting sausages.
他們在烤香腸
Now it's sundown.
現在太陽下山了
And now it's super hot in here.
然後這邊現在變超級熱鬧的
We'll all be out selling at night.
到晚上大家都出來賣東西
It's hot in here, too.
這裡也很熱鬧
And here's a coffee shop.
然後這邊有一個咖啡店
Then go over there and take a look.
然後走過去那邊看一看
I'm back in my room.
我回來房間了
I forgot to shoot first.
忘記要先拍了
This one's a fried fish.
這個是一個炸魚
And then we'll have dinner.
然後跟飯
And cucumbers.
還有小黃瓜
And fish truffles and soup.
還有魚露跟湯
And this one's kind of similar.
然後這個有點類似
That kind of life roll in Vietnam.
越南的那種生春捲
It's just a smaller one.
只是比較小顆小顆的
And this is the sauce.
然後給了醬料是這個
It's kind of hot, too.
也是有點辣辣的
And he's got a lot of lettuce down there.
然後他下面有附很多生菜
I think it's okay.
我覺得還不錯
I think he's kind of like a Vietnamese dish.
我覺得他有點像越南的料理
Because he's got this.
因為他有這種
When I was eating river powder in Vietnam,
我在越南吃河粉的時候
The ones in the dish they gave me.
他們給的那一盤菜裡面的那些
It's all the same.
料都很像
And then I bought one of these.
然後還有買了一個這個
Let's eat later.
等一下再來吃
It's supposed to be sweet.
應該是甜甜的東西
It's like sugar or something.
就是類似糖之類的
And then he's gonna make a little bit of it.
然後他會把它弄成一絲一絲的
I saw it in Bangkok.
在曼谷有看到過
All right, I'll eat.
好那我來吃飯
I kind of can't eat it.
我有點吃不下
This sauce.
這個醬
It's really hot.
真的好辣
I really can't stand it.
我真的有點受不了
Then there's four more.
然後還有四個
Let's keep it up.
唉  好繼續加油